Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're bringing you another elementary level lesson as a part
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家带来另一节初级课程，这是
of our interview series.
我们面试系列的一部分。
That's right.
没错。
This is part two of the interview series and the last part we talked about, well, a brief
这是面试系列的第二部分，上一部分我们讨论了，嗯，
introduction when you arrive to a job interview.
到达面试现场时的简短介绍。
But on this occasion, we're going to talk a little bit about yourself and your life.
但这次，我们要聊聊你自己和你的人生。
That's right.
没错。
That's the most personal part, I think, of an interview.
我觉得那是面试中最个人化的部分。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about
让我们听听今天的对话，稍后我们会回来进一步讨论
the things that you've heard.
你听到的内容。
Now, Miss Childs passed on your resume to me and I've had a chance to look it over.
嗯，Childs小姐，你的简历已经转交给我了，我也看过了。
I must say I'm quite impressed.
我得说，我印象非常深刻。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
我尽量让它简洁明了。
If there are any questions, please feel free to ask me.
如果有任何问题，请随时问我。
Well, yes, I do have a number of questions, but perhaps first you could give me a brief
嗯，是的，我确实有几个问题，但也许你可以先给我一个
overview.
简要概述。
I'd like to get a little bit of an idea of your background.
我想了解一下你的背景。
Yes, of course.
好的，当然。
Well, as you can see from the resume, I'm 27 and grew up in Brooklyn, New York, although
嗯，正如你从简历上看到的，我27岁，在纽约布鲁克林长大，不过
our family moved to London when I was quite young at around 16.
我们家在我很小的时候，大概16岁，搬到了伦敦。
Ah, I see.
啊，我明白了。
So you were actually educated in Europe.
所以你实际上是在欧洲接受的教育。
Yes, precisely.
是的，没错。
Although I was born in the US, I would definitely call London home.
虽然我出生在美国，但我绝对会把伦敦称为家。
But as you see, I've actually spent a lot of my life moving from country to country.
但如你所见，我一生中很多时间都在各国之间奔波。
My father was in the oil business before he retired, so we also spent a number of years
我父亲退休前从事石油行业，所以我们也在沙特阿拉伯
in Saudi Arabia, too.
住了好几年。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
So it seems you had quite an adventurous childhood.
看来你有一个相当冒险的童年。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
We were never still for too long, but now I'm really looking to settle down.
我们从来不会在一个地方待太久，但现在我真的很想安定下来。
I see.
我明白了。
Okay.
好的。
Well, let's move on to discuss your education, shall we?
嗯，那我们继续讨论你的教育背景，好吗？
Sure.
当然。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously this person had a very interesting life and they use some pretty interesting
显然，这个人有着非常有趣的生活，他们用了一些相当有趣的
words there.
词汇。
So why don't we take a look at five key words that we have prepared for you on Language
那我们来看看在“语言小贴士”环节中为你准备的五个关键词吧。
Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Language Takeaway.
Alright, so the first word that we have is right when Mr. Parsons talked to Miss Childs
好的，第一个词是当Parsons先生对Childs小姐说话时，
and he said that he was very impressed with her resume.
他说他对她的简历印象非常深刻。
Alright, so someone says I'm impressed when they think that something that you did or
好的，当某人认为你做的某件事或你的某些方面非常有趣、很好或比大多数人强时，
something about you is very interesting or good or better than most people's.
他们会说“I'm impressed”。
That's right.
没错。
So you're kind of amazed, you're kind of, you're like, wow.
所以你有点惊讶，有点，就像，哇。
And so this is an adjective.
这是一个形容词。
I am impressed.
我印象深刻。
That's right.
没错。
So teachers sometimes say this.
所以老师有时会这么说。
Maybe when you do really, really, really well on a test, they say, hey, Marco, I'm really
也许当你考试考得非常好时，他们会说，嘿，Marco，我真的
impressed.
印象深刻。
You got 99%.
你得了99分。
Parents say this to friends, family.
父母会对朋友、家人这么说。
So basically this is a way to say good job.
所以基本上这是一种说“做得好”的方式。
Wow.
哇。
Right.
对。
And there's also a verb.
还有一个动词形式。
So this is the adjective to be impressed and the verb form would be to impress someone.
所以这是形容词“to be impressed”，动词形式是“to impress someone”。
So that's obviously if you impress your teacher by studying, your teacher will be impressed.
所以如果你通过学习给老师留下深刻印象，老师就会印象深刻。
That's right.
没错。
And following that, Mr. Parson has some questions about Miss Child's background.
接着，Parsons先生对Childs小姐的背景有一些问题。
That's right.
没错。
He asked her for a brief overview of her background.
他请她简要概述一下她的背景。
So we have two interesting words there.
所以那里有两个有趣的词。
An overview.
概述。
What is an overview?
什么是概述？
An overview is like a summary.
概述就像总结。
It's basically a way to ask for someone to give you a lot of information in very few
基本上是一种要求别人用很少的
words.
话提供大量信息的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So you don't really want too much details.
所以你不需要太多细节。
You don't want somebody to tell you their life in detail.
你不想让别人详细讲述他们的一生。
You just want a brief summary.
你只想要一个简短的总结。
Right.
对。
So not, I was born on August 11th in 1979 and I was and then I went into this.
所以不是，我出生于1979年8月11日，然后我去了这个。
No, this is basic, simple, you know, this is where I'm from.
不，这是基础的、简单的，你知道，这就是我来自的地方。
This is where I went to school at the end.
这就是我最后上学的地方。
And well, he wanted a brief overview of her background.
嗯，他想要一个关于她背景的简要概述。
What exactly is her background?
她的背景到底是什么？
Well think about the word back.
嗯，想想“back”这个词。
Okay.
好的。
That means behind or in this case, background is your personal history.
那意味着“后面”或在这种情况下，“background”是你的个人经历。
So you could ask someone, what's your background?
所以你可以问某人，“你的背景是什么？”
It means where are you from or you know, what have you been doing up to now in your life?
这意味着你来自哪里，或者你知道，你到目前为止在生活中做了什么？
That's right.
没错。
And precisely when he asked her about her background, now she's starting to talk about
而正是当他问起她的背景时，她开始泛泛地谈论
her life in general terms.
她的生活。
As we said, it's an overview.
就像我们说的，这是一个概述。
So she said that she's 27 and she's from Brooklyn, etc.
所以她说她27岁，来自布鲁克林等等。
So she starts giving very general information about herself and her life.
所以她开始给出关于她自己和她的生活的非常一般的信息。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And when she starts to do this, Mr. Parson has more specific questions about her life
当她开始这样做时，帕森先生对她的生活有更具体的问题，
because he wants to know details.
因为他想知道细节。
So he asks her then where she was educated.
所以他接着问她是在哪里受的教育。
So this this phrase to be educated is very important.
所以这个短语“to be educated”非常重要。
That's right.
没错。
So he's asking her, you studied in Europe.
所以他问她，你在欧洲学习过。
That's right.
没错。
To be educated means to have someone teach you or to go to school somewhere.
受教育意味着有人教你，或者你在某个地方上学。
So for example, I was educated in America.
比如，我在美国受的教育。
Where were you educated, Marco?
马可，你在哪里受的教育？
I was educated in Chile.
我在智利受的教育。
Wow.
哇。
So you've been educated in a number of different places, right?
所以你在好几个不同的地方受过教育，对吧？
At home and in a different country.
在家乡和另一个国家。
Right.
对。
But you can also specify the university name, right?
但你也可以具体说明大学的名字，对吧？
For example, I was educated at Harvard.
比如，我在哈佛受的教育。
Can you say that?
可以这么说吗？
You can.
可以。
Or I was educated at a number of different schools.
或者我在好几所不同的学校受过教育。
So you can say I studied or I was educated.
所以你可以说“我学习过”或“我受过教育”。
All right.
好的。
And well, apparently she was moving around from Europe, United States.
而且，显然她一直在欧洲、美国之间辗转。
So Mr. Parson says, wow, it seems that you had an adventurous childhood.
所以帕森先生说，哇，看来你有一个充满冒险的童年。
Okay.
好的。
This is a great adjective, adventurous.
这是一个很棒的形容词，“爱冒险的”。
You can say a person is adventurous.
你可以说一个人是爱冒险的。
So Marco is very adventurous.
所以马可非常爱冒险。
He likes to jump out of airplanes.
他喜欢从飞机上跳下来。
But you can also say that an experience is adventurous, like moving around a lot as a
但你也可以说一段经历是充满冒险的，比如小时候经常搬家，
child.
就像这样。
Right.
没错。
So I guess adventurous can go hand in hand with exciting or very interesting, full of
所以我觉得“爱冒险的”可以和“令人兴奋的”或“非常有趣的”联系在一起，充满
emotion.
情感。
That's right.
没错。
So adventure, adventurous.
所以是冒险，爱冒险的。
So a person can be adventurous.
所以一个人可以是爱冒险的。
And we actually had a lesson about this when we describe personalities.
我们之前有一节课讲描述性格时，就提到过这个。
You can say someone is adventurous.
你可以说某人爱冒险。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好了。
Very good.
非常好。
So five key words that we just took a look at.
所以我们刚刚看了五个关键词。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back to talk a little
我们为什么不回去再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一聊。
bit more on Fluency Builder.
再讲一点关于流利度训练的内容。
Now Miss Childs passed on your resume to me and I've had a chance to look it over.
奇尔兹女士把你的简历转交给了我，我已经看过了。
I must say I'm quite impressed.
我得说，印象相当深刻。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
我尽量让它简洁明了。
If there are any questions, please feel free to ask me.
如果有任何问题，请随时问我。
Well, yes, I do have a number of questions, but perhaps first you could give me a brief
嗯，是的，我确实有几个问题，但也许你可以先给我一个简要的
overview.
概述。
I'd like to get a little bit of an idea of your background.
我想了解一下你的背景。
Yes, of course.
当然可以。
Well, as you can see from the resume, I'm 27 and grew up in Brooklyn, New York.
嗯，正如你在简历上看到的，我27岁，在纽约布鲁克林长大。
Although our family moved to London when I was quite young.
不过我们家在我很小的时候就搬到了伦敦。
At around 16.
大概16岁左右。
Ah, I see.
啊，我明白了。
So you were actually educated in Europe.
所以你实际上是在欧洲接受的教育。
Yes, precisely.
是的，没错。
Although I was born in the US, I would definitely call London home.
虽然我出生在美国，但我绝对把伦敦称为家。
But as you see, I've actually spent a lot of my life moving from country to country.
但如你所见，我一生中很多时间都在各国之间奔波。
My father was in the oil business before he retired.
我父亲退休前从事石油行业。
So we also spent a number of years in Saudi Arabia too.
所以我们也在沙特阿拉伯待过几年。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
So it seems you had quite an adventurous childhood.
看来你的童年相当冒险。
Absolutely.
没错。
We were never still for too long.
我们从来不会在一个地方待太久。
But now I'm really looking to settle down.
但现在我真的很想安定下来。
I see.
我明白了。
Okay, well, let's move on to discuss your education, shall we?
好的，那我们接着聊聊你的教育背景吧，好吗？
Sure.
当然。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So we have four phrases for you on Fluency Builder prepared.
我们准备了四个短语，放在流利度构建器里。
And let's start on with the first one.
我们先从第一个开始。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, so the very beginning, Mr. Parsons is continuing what he was saying in our first
好的，一开始，帕森斯先生继续他在我们第一部分说的话。
part.
部分。
So Mr. Parsons is talking about Rebecca's resume and he says, someone, the secretary,
帕森斯先生在谈论丽贝卡的简历，他说，有人，秘书，
she passed it on to me.
她把它转交给了我。
So this verb, to pass on, this is really important.
所以这个动词，to pass on，非常重要。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Well, the secretary, Ms. Childs, passed on Rebecca's resume.
嗯，秘书，蔡尔兹女士，转交了丽贝卡的简历。
That basically means she, Ms. Childs received it and she didn't keep it.
这基本上意味着她，蔡尔兹女士收到了它，但没有保留。
She passed it on or she gave it to another person.
她把它转交或给了另一个人。
In this case, Mr. Parsons.
在这个例子中，是帕森斯先生。
Okay, so this implies, this shows that something doesn't stay with one person, like you said,
好的，所以这暗示，这表明某物不会停留在一个人手里，就像你说的，
Marco, but it moves from one person to another person.
马可，而是从一个人传到另一个人。
So for example, my mother told me to pass this message on to you.
比如，我妈妈让我把这个消息转告给你。
The message is not for me, it's for you.
消息不是给我的，是给你的。
I think also with physical traits, like maybe if your mother had green eyes, you can maybe
我觉得也可以用在身体特征上，比如如果你妈妈有绿眼睛，你也许可以
say my mom passed on her eye color on to me.
说妈妈把她的眼睛颜色遗传给了我。
That's right.
没错。
So, you got it from her.
所以，你从她那里得到了它。
Alright, so that's what happened with the resume and he said, well, she passed it on
好的，这就是简历的情况，他说，嗯，她把它转交了，
and I've had the chance to look it over.
我有机会看了一下。
Okay, so think about this as a chunk, as a group of words that we use together to look
好的，把这个看作一个整体，一组我们经常一起用的词，to look
something over.
something over。
We can say, hey, Marco, when you have a minute, can you look this over for me?
我们可以说，嘿，马可，你有空的时候，能帮我看一下这个吗？
Okay, so that means to examine or to take a look.
好的，所以这意味着检查或看一看。
Take a look at, that's right.
看一看，没错。
So to look something over or to look it over.
所以 to look something over 或 to look it over。
Alright, so basically to examine, maybe in close detail, right?
好的，基本上就是检查，可能仔细地看，对吧？
You actually take the time to read it.
你实际上花时间去读它。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And then later on, they started talking about her background.
然后后来，他们开始谈论她的背景。
As we know, she was from Brooklyn, she grew up in Brooklyn and then she moved to London.
我们知道，她来自布鲁克林，在布鲁克林长大，然后搬到了伦敦。
And so Rebecca described how she spent most of her life moving from country to country.
丽贝卡描述了她如何大部分时间从一个国家搬到另一个国家。
Okay, from country to country.
好的，从一个国家到另一个国家。
This means that she moved to many different countries.
这意味着她搬到了许多不同的国家。
Okay, so if I live in America all my life, I never moved from country to country.
好的，如果我一生都住在美国，我从来没有从一个国家搬到另一个国家。
You can say this about many different things, from place to place, from town to town.
你可以用这个说法来形容很多不同的事情，从一个地方到另一个地方，从一个城镇到另一个城镇。
It means that you live in one, you go from one place to another.
这意味着你住在一个地方，从一个地方到另一个地方。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, if you replace the noun country, you can say from town to town.
就像你说的，如果你替换名词 country，你可以说 from town to town。
You can even say from house to house.
你甚至可以说 from house to house。
I went from house to house asking for money.
我挨家挨户要钱。
That's right.
没错。
So from to.
所以 from to。
Exactly.
正是。
So from something to something.
所以从某物到某物。
And for our final phrase, she was talking about how she's moved around so much that
对于我们的最后一个短语，她谈到她搬了太多次，
she's actually ready to settle down.
以至于她真的准备好安定下来了。
Okay, to settle down.
好的，to settle down。
This is a really important phrase and I think it's something a lot of people do when they're
这是一个非常重要的短语，我觉得很多人会在
maybe in their 30s or 40s.
三十多岁或四十多岁时这样做。
They don't want to move anymore.
他们不想再搬家了。
So to settle down means to stay in one place.
所以 to settle down 意味着待在一个地方。
Exactly.
正是。
So you stay in one place.
所以你待在一个地方。
And it can have a lot of different meanings as well.
它也可以有很多不同的含义。
For example, to get married, many people say that's settling down.
比如，结婚，很多人说那就是安定下来。
It means you want to stay in one place and have a family.
这意味着你想待在一个地方，组建家庭。
Or to buy a house because it means that you will live there for a long time.
或者买房子，因为这意味着你会在那里住很长时间。
Exactly.
正是。
So to settle down.
所以 to settle down。
So a lot of interesting phrases there, a lot of words and this is, as we said, part two
那里有很多有趣的短语，很多词汇，这是，正如我们说的，我们系列的第二部分。
of our series.
系列。
So I think it would be worthy for us to listen to this dialogue one last time and we'll be
所以我觉得值得我们再听一遍这段对话，然后我们会
back to talk a little bit more.
回来再聊一会儿。
Now Miss Childs passed on your resume to me and I've had a chance to look it over.
现在，蔡尔兹女士把你的简历转交给了我，我有机会看了一下。
I must say I'm quite impressed.
我必须说，我印象非常深刻。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
I've tried to keep it short and clear.
我尽量让它简短明了。
If there are any questions, please feel free to ask me.
如果有任何问题，请随时问我。
Well, yes, I do have a number of questions, but perhaps first you could give me a brief
嗯，是的，我确实有很多问题，但也许你可以先给我一个简要的
overview.
概述。
I'd like to get a little bit of an idea of your background.
我想了解一下你的背景。
Yes, of course.
好的，当然。
Well, as you can see from the resume, I'm 27 and grew up in Brooklyn, New York, although
嗯，正如你从简历上看到的，我27岁，在纽约布鲁克林长大，不过
our family moved to London when I was quite young at around 16.
我们全家在我大约16岁还很年轻的时候就搬到了伦敦。
I see.
我明白了。
So you were actually educated in Europe.
所以你实际上是在欧洲接受的教育。
Yes, precisely.
是的，没错。
Although I was born in the US, I would definitely call London home.
虽然我出生在美国，但我绝对会把伦敦称为家。
But as you see, I've actually spent a lot of my life moving from country to country.
但如你所见，我一生中很多时间都在各国之间奔波。
My father was in the oil business before he retired, so we also spent a number of years
我父亲退休前从事石油行业，所以我们也在沙特阿拉伯
in Saudi Arabia too.
住了几年。
Very interesting.
非常有趣。
So it seems you had quite an adventurous childhood.
看来你有一个相当冒险的童年。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
We were never still for too long, but now I'm really looking to settle down.
我们从未在一个地方待太久，但现在我真的想安定下来。
I see.
我明白了。
Okay.
好的。
Well, let's move on to discuss your education, shall we?
那么，我们来讨论一下你的教育背景，好吗？
Sure.
当然。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So this is part two of a 10-part series of the interviews.
这是10集系列采访的第二部分。
Now we just talked about the background, and I think there are different ways of talking
刚才我们讨论了背景，我认为谈论背景有不同的方式，
about your background, right?
对吧？
This is maybe your personal background.
这可能是你的个人背景。
That's right.
没错。
So you can talk about your personal history, your personal background, where you were born,
所以你可以谈论你的个人经历、个人背景、你出生在哪里、
where you were educated, where you grew up.
在哪里接受教育、在哪里长大。
But a lot of times we also have to talk about other parts of our background, like our work
但很多时候我们还需要谈论背景的其他部分，比如工作
background or like next week, our educational background.
背景，或者像下周要讲的教育背景。
That's right.
没错。
So part three, we're going to take a look at your educational background.
所以第三部分，我们将关注你的教育背景。
And it's going to be very important because I think in many interviews, people have a
这会非常重要，因为我认为在很多面试中，人们很难
hard time describing what they studied or maybe describing exactly what they did during
描述他们学过什么，或者很难准确描述他们在大学、
university or college or master's degree or something.
学院或硕士期间具体做了什么。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And we're not talking about elementary school or high school.
我们不是在谈论小学或高中。
We're specifically talking about university background here.
我们这里专门谈论的是大学背景。
So like you're saying, Marco, what was your major?
所以就像你说的，Marco，你的专业是什么？
What was your minor?
你的辅修是什么？
What was your area of study?
你的研究领域是什么？
These are great, great, great phrases that are very important for an interview.
这些都是非常、非常、非常重要的短语，对面试很关键。
And so we hope that if you have any questions, you'll let us know.
所以我们希望，如果你有任何问题，请告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com and stay tuned for next week's episode.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com，请继续关注下周的节目。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we'll see everyone on the website and until next time.
那么，我们网站上见，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Thanks everyone.
谢谢大家。